John and Ginny Dildine collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Sound Recordings
  - AFC 1975/001: SR053, Recorded: 1961-12-17, RAA 54529; 52:53
    37:20 "Wondrous Love" McCurdy, a cappella
    40:50 No recording. Blank tape.
    42:10 Dildine introduces the next song.
    42:38 "Clinch Mountain" McCurdy
    44:38 Dildine introduces the next song.
    45:01 "Jug of Punch" Tommy Makem and the Clancy Brothers
    48:13 "One Eyed Riley" Tommy Makem and the Clancy Brothers
    49:58 "Railroad Bill," closing theme. Dildine concludes the broadcast.
  - AFC 1975/001: SR054, Recorded: unknown [may be 1962-01-04], RAA 54530; 29:02; [This seems to be a live recording session of Bill Roberts. He sings and plays guitar except where noted. The date and place of this recording is not known.]
    This seems to be a live recording session of Bill Roberts. He sings and plays guitar except where noted. The date and place of this recording is not known.
    Start "Loose Your Money" (take 2) Roberts
    2:55 "Ain't That Rockin'" (take 1) Roberts
    5:51 "Hey Ho Mary" (take 1) Roberts
    9:00 "Hey Ho Mary" (take 2) Roberts
    11:50 "James Alley Blues" (Take 1) Roberts
    12:42 "James Alley Blues" (Take 2) Roberts
    12:50 "James Alley Blues" (Take 3) Roberts
    17:00 "James Alley Blues" (Take 4) Roberts
    17:38 "James Alley Blues" (Take 5) Roberts
    22:07 "I looked down the road just as far as I could see," first line Roberts, vocal and harmonica
    25:19 "Hey Joe, where you going with that money in your hand," (first line) Roberts
    26:30 blank tape
    27:03 "You gotta walk muddy waters" (first line) Roberts
  - AFC 1975/001: SR055, Recorded: unknown [may be 1962-01-04], RAA54531; 26:42
    This seems to be a continuation of the recording session recording session for Bill Roberts. See SR054. He sings and plays guitar except where noted.
    Start "Loose our Money" Roberts
    2:44 "Telephone Blues" Roberts
    4:44 "Ain't that Rockin'" Roberts, unidentified person playing harmonica
    7:36 "Hey Ho Mary" Roberts, unidentified person playing harmonica
    10:27 "Careless Love" Roberts, unidentified person playing harmonica
    13:55 ["Get it Well"] or perhaps ["That's the Way It Goes"] Roberts
    16:27 "James Alley Blues" Roberts
    20:52 "De Kalb Blues" Roberts
    23:32 "Hey Joe" Roberts
    26:42 End
  - AFC 1975/001: SR056, Recorded: 1962-01-04, RAA 54532; 24:01
    Start "My Bonnie" Roberts
    3:23 "Poor Man but a Good Man" Roberts
    5:41 "Stackolee" Roberts
    9:52 "Noted Rider" Roberts
    12:30 unidentified Roberts, harmonica solo
    16:04 "Frankie and albert" Roberts
    20:29 "Fare Thee Well" Roberts
    24:01 End
  - AFC 1975/001: SR057, Recorded: 1962-01-04, RAA 54533; 29:21
    Start blank
    0:27 "Muddy Water" Roberts
    3:27 "12 Gates to the City" Roberts
    4:52 talking, brief on the harmonica Roberts
    5:05 unidentified Roberts, guitar, vocal and harmonica
    8:05 tuning the guitar
    11:30 "Bottle Up and Go" Roberts, guitar, vocal and harmonica
    14:08 blank
    14:41 "My Mama Don't Allow Me" Roberts, guitar, vocal and harmonica
    17:55 "Careless Love" Roberts, guitar, vocal and harmonica
    23:13 unidentified Roberts
    24:58 "Key to the Highway" Roberts
  - AFC 1975/001: SR058, Recorded: 1962-01-04, RAA 54534; 29:42
    Start noise
    0:51 "Frankie and Albert" Roberts
    1:45 talking
    2:07 "Keep on Truckin' Mama" Roberts
    6:22 talking
    8:22 "Fare Thee Well" Roberts
    11:54 talking and a short bit of music
    12:47 "Motherless Child" (take 1) Roberts
    13:44 "Motherless Child" (take 2) Roberts
    17:50 blank
    18:10 unidentified guitar solo Roberts
    19:10 "Rabbit on the Ground" Roberts
    25:01 talking and blank
    25:22 "Keys to the Highway" Roberts
    29:42 End
  - AFC 1975/001: SR059, Recorded: 1962-03-25, RXG 0740; 15:11
    This is a recording for part of a John Dildine radio broadcast. He plays selections from several phonograph records.
    Start Dildine says that the New Lost City Ramblers learned the next song from a recording by Uncle Dave Macon.
    1:00 "Hold the Woodpile Down" New Lost City Ramblers [Mike Seeger, John Cohen and Tom Paley]
    3:45 Dildine says the next song is from a John Lomax recording [Lubbock, Texas, 1937] of J.C. Fowler, Elrick Buckner, and Alva Ruffner [spelling of names is ‘best guess'].
    4:20 "Devil's Dream" Fowler, Buckner and Ruffner
    6:13 Dildine discusses John and Alan Lomax. The next song is from an Alan Lomax album titled "Folksong Saturday Night."
    6:57 "Inchin' Along" Alan Lomax, Peggy Seeger, Guy Carawan, John Cole and Sammy Stokes
    10:12 Dildine introduces the next song.
    10:44 "Soldier's Joy" Nashville Washboard Band
    12:21 Dildine closes the radio broadcast.
    12:37 Closing theme "Railroad Bill"
  - AFC 1975/001: SR060, Recorded: unknown, RAA54535; 49:33
    This is a recording for a John Dildine radio broadcast. He plays recordings of traditional folk songs of Great Britain from a set of recordings put together by Alan Lomax and Peter Kennedy.
    Start "Railroad Bill," the opening theme. Dildine introduces the program. He will next play two versions of "The Elfin Night."
    3:21 version 1, "An Acre of Land" Bob and Ron Cooper
    5:07 version 2, Strawberry Land" Thomas Moran
    6:07 Dildine introduces the next song.
    7:03 "The False Knight on the Road" Frank Quinn
    8:57 "The Outlandish Knight" or "Six Pretty Maids" Fred Jordan
    12:04 Dildine talks about the recordings he is playing. He does a station break for The Showboat Lounge. He introduces the next song.
    14:18 "The Twa Sisters" [This version is probably called "Minorie"] John Strichen
    16:06 Several versions of "Lord Randall" several performers
    19:36 Dildine discusses the previous version of "Lord Randall" and identifies the performers. He introduces the next set of songs and the performers.
    22:05 Various versions of a song called "Edward" several performers
    26:06 Dildine introduces the next songs.
    27:11 "The Cruel Mother" Thomas Moran
    29:00 "The Broomfield Wager" Cyril Poacher
    32:33 Dildine discusses the albums in the series of recordings he is playing. He introduces the next song.
    33:31 "The Jovial Tradesman" Ron and Bob Cooper
    35:12 Dildine does a station break for The Shadows. He introduces the next song.
    37:00 "The Roaming Journeyman" Paddy Duran
    37:53 "The Candlelight Fisherman" Phil Hammond
    39:35 The Canny Shepard Laddie" Jimmie White
    40:23 Dildine discusses the previous songs and introduces the next song.
    41:20 "The Dairy Maid" John McGuire, tin whistle
    42:27 "Green Brooms" Shawn [or perhaps Shaun] McDonaugh
    44:51 Dildine discusses the albums from which he played the songs for the night's program. He closes the broadcast with "Railroad Bill," the theme song.
    49:33 End
  - AFC 1975/001: SR061, Recorded: 1962-07, RXG 0741; 40:10
    This was recorded in Chicago for future broadcast of a John Dildine radio show. His guests are George and Gerry Armstrong and Howie Mitchell. The venue for the recording seems to be the Armstrongs home.
    Start "Shady Grove" George, Gerry and Howie
    2:09 Dildine introduces the performers. He asks George why he is interested in the [folk music] material. George answers and Gerry joins in.
    5:28 "Who Killed Cock Robin" Gerry [vocal]
    7:56 Gerry says that she learned the previous song from Richard Chase. Gerry, George and John discuss learning folk songs. They prefer to learn directly from people or else from recordings, rather than from books. They discuss how the Armstrongs became interested in folk music. George says that this evening they've been playing dulcimers made by Howie Mitchell.
    13:25 "My Home's Across the Blue Ridge Mountains" Gerry, George and Howie
    16:20 George says he learned the previous song from Frank Profit. John asks Howie about a recording he recently made for Folk Legacy Records. Howie and John talk about the mouth-bow and about Jimmy Driftwood.
    20:25 "Skip to My Lou" Howie [mouth-bow], George and Gerry [the recording quality from here to about 22:45 is very poor]
    22:45 An unidentified Morris Dance George [bag pipes?], Ginny Dildine [drum], Gerry [guitar], Howie [dulcimer]
    24:50 The group discusses the previous song. George says that he and Gerry are also involved with folk games, folk dance, etc. in addition to the music. They discuss folk music and traditions beyond the United States.
    34:25 [A shape-note hymn] ‘"This Old World Is Full of Sorrow" Gerry, George and Howie [Their version is very similar to "This Old World," a Unitarian hymn]
    35:42 Howie says that he learned to play the next song from Jean Ritchie.
    36:30 "What a Are You Gonna Do with the Baby-o" Howie [mouth-bow], George [dulcimer]
    38:36 John asks George to play the bagpipes. George declines because of the late hour and because children are asleep in the house. Instead he says he'll play a tune call "Nonesuch" on the practice [bagpipe] chanter. [The tape ends before this song is played.]
    40:10 End
  - AFC 1975/001: SR062, Recorded: 1962-08-05, RXG 0742; 35:02
    This a recording for a John Dildine radio broadcast. Most of the program is of Ellen and Robin Christenson which was recorded in St. Louis at the home of Peter and Judy Weston. The last part of the program is two songs from a Folk Legacy recording of Frank Profitt. It is continued on SR063.
    Start "Railroad Bill" opening theme, recorded
    0:39 John Dildine talks about a trip that he, his wife [Ginny Dildine] and Howie Mitchell recently took to the mid-west. They recorded several performers in Chicago and St. Louis. Tonight he is going to play a session with Ellen and Robin Christenson.
    1:13 "Little Birdie" Ellen and Robin [banjo and guitar]
    5:23 John and Ellen talk about Ellen and her sister and a record they made. John and Robin talk about two records that he made. They talk about how they developed their interest in folk music. They talk about "kitchen songs" and other types of folk songs.
    10:15 "Woody" Robin [vocal]
    13:05 Robin says that he learned this song from a girl at Swarthmore College. Her name is Ruth [Kellen] and she lives in Washington D.C. He's also heard other versions of the song, as has Dildine.
    14:20 Dildine does a station break.
    15:37 Dildine asks the Christenson's to perform a song for children. The discuss children's songs.
    17:58 Unidentified song. The first line is "Ducks in the millpond, geese in the clover" Robin and Ellen
    19:30 Dildine does a station break.
    20:00 Dildine asks Ellen how she got interested in folk music. She replies.
    21:00 "One Morning, One Morning, One Morning in May" Ellen [vocal and guitar]
    23:48 Dildine asks for one more song.
    24:45 Unidentified song. The title may be ["Sangree" or "Singree"] Robin and Ellen
    27:10 Dildine thanks the Christensons. He then talks about other tapes he plans to play on future broadcasts. He talks about Frank Profitt.
    30:19 "Trifling Woman" Frank Profitt [vocal and banjo, recorded]
    32:37 "Cluck Old hen" Frank Profitt [vocal and banjo, recorded]
    35:02 End
  - AFC 1975/001: SR063, Recorded: 1962-08-05, RXG 0743; 15:25
    This is a continuation of SR062, a John Dildine radio broadcast. This part of the program is recorded songs of Frank Profitt, vocal and fretless banjo.
    Start Dildine discusses Profitt's recording of "Cluck Old Hen." Dildine says that Profitt is playing a home made, fretless banjo.
    1:13 Dildine does a station break.
    2:14 Dildine talks about Profitt's recordings.
    3:36 "Morning Fair" [Dildine says that this is a version of "The Butcher Boy"] Profitt
    6:26 "Booted and Spurred" Profitt
    7:53 Dildine says that the previous song is a Child Ballad, "Bonnie James Campbell" and it has the most complete text of all the versions Childe collected.
    8:50 "Lord Randall" [a Child Ballad] Profitt
    12:15 Dildine closes his radio program.
    13:20 "Railroad Bill" [closing theme, recorded]
    15:25 End
  - AFC 1975/001: SR064 (1), Recorded: 1962-10-12, RXG 0744; 26:16
    This two part recording is a concert performance by Carol Hedin and Donal Leace at the University of Virginia. Carol Hedin is on this portion of the tape.
    Start Carol Hedin talks about Paul Clayton.
    0:48 "Bonnie Love" Hedin (vocal and autoharp)
    3:35 Hedin introduces the next song.
    4:48 "Tranquil" Hedin (vocal and autoharp)
    8:42 Hedin introduces the next song.
    9:05 "Hold the Wind" Hedin (a cappella)
    11:17 Hedin introduces the next song.
    12:10 "Eggs and Marrow Bones" Hedin (vocal and guitar)
    15:30 Hedin talks about her trip to Seattle during the World's Fair. She introduces the next song.
    17:55 "Sun, Dry My Tears" Hedin (vocal and guitar)
    21:22 Hedin introduces the next song. It is a Jimmy Driftwood song.
    22:30 "The Mixed up Family" Hedin (vocal and guitar)
    26:16 End
  - AFC 1975/001: SR064 (2), Recorded: 1962-10-12, RXG 0744; 27:03
    This two part recording is a concert performance by Carol Hedin and Donal Leace at the University of Virginia. Donal Leace is on this portion of the tape. The recording quality is not very good, so some of the spoken words and sung words are difficult to understand.
    Start [The song began prior to recording being started.] "Run mountain, Chug aLittle Hill" [probably Hedin and Leace]
    1:22 "Children Go Where I Send Thee" Leace (vocal and guitar)
    4:38 "Leace tells the story of a mother and son. He introduces the next song.
    8:09 This song is a version of the "Silkie of Sule Skerry." Leace called it something like "the Silkie Sister" Leace (vocal and guitar)
    12:55 Leace talks about wanting to attend the University of Mississippi. He introduces the next song as "Daddy Old Daddy." He says heard Miriam Makeba and a man perform it. The first line is "Darling Go Home, Your Husband is I'll." It was written by Ms. Makeba.
    15:30 "One More Dance" Leace (vocal and guitar)
    18:05 Leace talks about being in New York City. He and a (girl) friend talk with Marlene Dietrich about her beauty secrets. He introduces the next song. He says he heard it performed by Dave Van Ronk and Carolyn Hester. His version is informed by both.
    20:28 "The House of the Rising Sun" Leace (vocal and guitar)
    25:25 Leace talks about the "Baptist cult."
    27:03 End
  - AFC 1975/001: SR065 (1), Recorded: 1962-10-12, RXG 0744; 37:47
    This is the first part of a concert performance at the University of Virginia by Allen Damron. The second part is on SR065 (2).
    Start Damron introduces the next song.
    1:03 "Hi Jolly - Ho Jolly" Damron (banjo)
    3:21 Damron introduces himself and the next song.
    4:10 Unidentified song Damron (banjo)
    6:32 Damron talks as he tunes his banjo. He says a bit about himself.
    9:09 "Alberta" ["let your hair hang low"] Damron (banjo)
    9:59 "Damron introduces the next song. He says it is sung by Mariachi bands in south Texas where he is from.
    12:05 Unidentified song, in Spanish Damon (guitar)
    15:19 Damon talks.
    15:45 Unidentified song Damon (guitar)
    18:12 Damon says he attends (or attended) the University of Texas. He talks about some people he met there.
    19:22 "Tip Toe through the Tulips" Damon (guitar)
    21:14 Damon introduces the next song.
    22:03 "Come Little Donkey, Come" Damon (banjo)
    24:20 Damon tunes his banjo and talks.
    25:22 "Michael Row Your Boat Ashore" Damon (banjo)
    27:49 Damon says the next song is a request. He tunes his guitar.
    28:58 "Nancy whiskey" [also known as "Carlton Weaver"] Damon (guitar)
    32:47 Damon is joined by Carol Hedin
    33:25 "Jack of Diamonds" Damron and Hedin (guitar)
    35:26 "Copper kettle" Damron and Hedin (guitar)
    37:47 End
  - AFC 1975/001: SR065 (2), Recorded: 1962-10-12, RXG 0744; 30:59
    This is the second part of a concert performance at the University of Virginia by Allen Damron. The first part is on SR065 (1).
    Start Damron talks about what it might be like to attend a Southern Baptist church.
    4:32 Unidentified song Damron (guitar)
    6:30 Unidentified song Damron (guitar)
    8:59 Damron introduces the next song.
    9:30 "Old Blue" Damron (guitar)
    13:57 "Keep My Skillet Good and Greasy" Damron (guitar)
    The first line of the version as he sings it is: "Well I'm goin' down town, I'm gonna buy me a jug of brandy"
    16:32 Damron introduces the next song. He says it was written by Pete Seeger.
    17:58 "The Bell of Rhymney" Damron (guitar)
    21:17 Carol Hedin joins Damron. Guitar being tuned. The next song is introduced.
    22:25 "There's a Hole in the Bucket" Damron and Hedin (guitar)
    26:44 They are joined by an unidentified man. Damron introduces the next song. Tuning of guitar and banjo.
    28:40 "Down by the Riverside" [The sound cuts out soon after the song begins.] Damron, Hedin and unidentified man
    30:59 End
  - AFC 1975/001: SR066, Recorded: ca. 1962, RAA54536; 21:41
    This is a set of solo instrumental performances by Pat Webb.
    Start unidentified Webb, dulcimer
    3:30 "Lodi" Webb, guitar
    5:40 "Ode to Dylan Thomas" Webb, guitar
    10:10 "Skid Row Blues" Webb, guitar
    12:57 square dance medley Webb, guitar
    14:50 unidentified Webb, guitar
    18:29 "Big Bill" Webb, guitar
    21:41 End
  - AFC 1975/001: SR067, Recorded: ca. 1962, RXG 0746; 37:45
    This is a John Dildine recording of the Beers family, Bob, Evelyn and their daughter Marty. It was recorded in St. Louis, probably in the Beers' home.
    Start A song is being played on the fiddle with rhythm being played in the background.
    1:25 Dildine introduces Bob and Evelyn Beers. Bob say that the previous song is a Cherokee fiddle tune. The rhythm (or beating) we heard is called "straw beating." A reed or straw is tapped against the fiddle. They talk about dancing dolls [e.g., limber Jacks] also used to provide rhythm.
    4:38 "The Conufman's (sic) Rambles" fiddle and straw beating
    5:54 Dildine asks Bob Beers how he learned the fiddle. Bob answers. Dildine asks Bob about the psaltery that Bob has in front of him. Bob answers.
    9:35 "Johnny Comes a Courtin'" Evelyn (vocal), Bob (psaltery) and Marty Beers, their daughter, singing harmony
    12:43 Dildine and Bob talk about the psaltery.
    13:36 "The Wind and the Rain" Bob (psaltery), Evelyn (vocal)
    16:55 Dildine and the Beers talk about the phonograph records they have made. Bob talks about his grandfather and other old fiddlers he know and/or from whom he learned. He introduces the next song.
    21:08 "The Man from Montana" Bob (a capella)
    24:03 Bob and Dildine talk about the previous song. They talk about the songs of Keith Clark.
    25:34 "Old Jim Gray" Bob and Evelyn (psaltery)
    27:46 Bob says that the previous song was based upon the true story of a runaway slave.
    29:23 "One Morning, One Morning, One Morning in May" Bob and Evelyn (psaltery)
    32:12 The Beers say that they learned the previous song from Char Daniels. They talk about from whom she learned it.
    34:00 "Bonnie George Campbell" Bob and Evelyn (psaltery)
    37:33 Dildine thanks the Beers.
    37:45 End
  - AFC 1975/001: SR068, Recorded: ca. 1962, RXG 0747; 28:38
    This is a recording of a John Dildine radio broadcast. The Christenson portion is an extract of SR062. He also interviews Tossi Aaron and Seamus Ennis.
    Start Dildine introduces Robin and Ellen Christenson.
    0:28 "Little birdie" Robin and Ellen
    4:35 Dildine talks with Robin and Ellen about their recordings and how they developed their interest in folk music. They talk about "kitchen songs" and other kinds of folk songs.
    8:13 "Woody" [May also be called "I'm a Poor Country Boy"] Robin (vocal)
    16:06 Dildine introduces Tossi Aaron.
    16:25 "Black is the Color of My True Love's Hair" Aaron (a cappella)
    13:06 Dildine interviews Aaron. They discuss the previous song. They talk about a range of topics related to Aarons' songs and how they evolve over time, and how she came to be a performer.
    20:30 Dildine interviews Seamus Ennis
    21:33 Unidentified song Ennis (a cappella)
    22:10 Ennis talks about a bird that he calls a corn crake.
    22:45 Ennis continues the previous song.
    24:05 Dildine and Ennis talk about the corn crake. They talk about carrying on the traditions in the city and in the country. Ennis discusses his involvement with a children's television program.
    27:29 unidentified song Ennis [penny whistle]
    28:08 Ennis recites a short [poem].
    28:31 Dildine says goodnight.
    28:38 End
  - AFC 1975/001: SR069, Recorded: 1963-02-03, RXG 0748; 24:01
    This is Part 1 of a recording for a John Dildine radio broadcast. Part 2 is on SR070. The part of the program is recordings of The Clancy Brothers and Tommy Makem.
    Start "Opening theme "Railroad Bill." Dildine opens the broadcast. He says that the show will consist mainly of new recordings by Pete Seeger and of The Clancy Brothers with Tommy Makem.
    3:25 "O-Donahugh" Clancy Brothers and Makem
    5:12 "I'll Tell My Ma" [also known as "the Boys won't Leave the Girls Alone"] Clancy Brothers and Makem
    6:55 "Wild Mountain Thyme" [also known as "Will you Go, Lassie Go"] Clancy Brothers and Makem
    10:07 Dildine gives the titles of the three previous songs. He then does a station break.
    12:29 "The Day We Went to Rathsay-O" Clancy Brothers and Makem
    14:56 "Mairi's Wedding" Clancy Brothers and Makem
    17:03 "Singing Bird" Clancy Brothers and Makem
    20:10 Dildine introduces the next song.
    20:56 "Holy Ground" Clancy Brothers and Makem
    23:28 Dildine does a station break.
  - AFC 1975/001: SR070, Recorded: 1963-02-03, RXG 0749; 32:45
    This is Part 2 of a recording for a John Dildine radio broadcast. Part 1 is on SR069. This part of the program is recordings of The Clancy Brothers and Tommy Makem, and of Pete Seeger from his new album "The Bitter and the Sweet."
    Start Dildine introduces the next song.
    0:42 "South Australia" Clancy Brothers and Tommy Makem
    2:42 Dildine introduces the next song.
    3:26 "MacPherson's Lament" Clancy Brothers and Tommy Makem
    7:04 Dildine introduces the next song.
    7:45 "Wild Colonial Boy" Clancy Brothers and Tommy Makem
    10:54 Pete Seeger introduces the next song. He credits his brother, Mike Seeger, for telling him the "secret" to playing it.
    11:25 "Old Joe Clark" Pete Seeger
    14:32 Dildine talks about the previous song. He does a break for a commercial. He introduces the next song.
    16:15 "Windy Old Weather" Pete Seeger
    20:22 Dildine talks about the use of singing in protest movements. He introduces the next song.
    21:35 "We Shall over Come" Pete Seeger
    26:21 "Turn, Turn, Turn" Pete Seeger
    29:30 Dildine talks about the previous song. He closes the broadcast.
    30:02 "Railroad Bill" The closing theme.
    32:45 End
  - AFC 1975/001: SR071, Recorded: ca. 1963, RXG 0750; 28:57
    This tape is a recording for a John Dildine radio broadcast. Most of the tape is an interview with Judy Collins. She has just released an album called "Judy Collins #3." No songs are played on this tape. This interview is concluded on SR145-1 Note: There is a folder in the collection for this SR. The note in the folder indicates a second tape of the Judy Collins session which includes the songs "The Dove," "Deportee" and "Farewell."
    Start Dildine introduces a live guest, Judy Collins. Dildine and Collins talk about her singing and professional aspirations.
    4:21 Collins and Dildine introduce the next song, "Anathea."
    6:21 The song is not on the tape. Dildine asks Collins "why she sings, what she's trying to say, where she got involved with the music, and why she sings the way she does." Collins responds.